HAZEL WHITFIELD

Sanford, Florida · (407) 310 - 5026

hazeljpw@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Website | GitHub

Professional with over 7 years experience in analytical thinking, data handling, problem solving, ethical awareness, compliance with company policies and procedures, collaborating with diverse teams and excelling under pressure. Transitioning from an accounting background to a career in technology. Driven by a passion for troubleshooting and dedicated to simplifying people's lives by resolving errors and enhancing user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Vanilla JavaScript, React, React Native, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, Git, GitHub, Firebase, Netlify, Postman, Android Studio, Figma, Visual Studio, Windows, MacOs.

PROJECTS

- Sanford Sweets (Web App)
 - https://sanford-sweets.netlify.app This front-end web app for a model cottage business is a visually appealing and user-friendly platform that provides essential information about the business and its products. It's built using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and React to ensure an engaging and responsive user experience. It serves as an important tool for promoting the business and connecting with potential customers.
- Sanford Sweets (Mobile App) This React Native-based mobile app for Sanford Sweet features a brighter
 design and a set of key features designed to improve the user experience on Android devices. Android
 Studio is used as the development environment and emulator, ensuring compatibility and a smooth
 performance. This mobile app serves as a valuable tool for enhancing the business's presence and
 engaging with mobile users.
- Job Hunt Progress This project is designed to facilitate the tracking of job hunt journeys. It is a dynamic Node.js application built using the Express framework in conjunction with the EJS view engine. This is a full-stack project with a primary emphasis on backend development. MongoDB ATLAS was utilized for the database.
- Personal Portfolio

https://hazelwhitfield.netlify.app/ - My portfolio project was created using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap. With a simple yet beautiful design, I showcase my information, skills, and projects.
Personal Portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Accounting Specialist - Senior Accounting Specialist - CareerSource Central Florida
 Accounting Specialist - CareerSource Central Florida

August 2019 - November 2022

Managed financial tasks in a non-profit company, including accounts payable, employee reimbursements, and expense tracking for departments. Facilitated grant reimbursements, provided training and reviewed contracts in a dynamic corporate setting.

• Staff Accountant - M. Kermali CPA, PA

April 2017 - July 2019

Meticulous bookkeeping and adherence to financial regulations. Collaborated closely with the small team and diverse clients to resolve any issues and achieve objectives.

• Staff Accountant - M. Stewart & Company

December 2015 - April 2017

Maintained accurate financial records, reconciling accounts, and producing insightful financial reports as a vital contribution within a small team, all with the aim of achieving client-centric objectives in compliance with accounting practices.

EDUCATION

• Full Stack Bootcamp

2023 Nucamp Bootcamp

Completed the 2023 Nucamp Bootcamp, gaining essential skills in both front-end and back-end web development and laying a strong foundation for future growth in the field.

 Office Information System (Business & Office Administration Services) | Focus in Accounting 2011-2023 ACLC College - Philippines